{
    "id": "b53eaf0671fe496fa3a2bcdee5e2fe89",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I heard the song ………………. the radio?",
            "description": "We use on with radio and television.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "in",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8c69c8203b7142cf8c3c102b777cc505"
        },
        {
            "question": "Identify the kind of sentence: Have a nice day.",
            "description": "An imperative sentence is a command, prayer, request or wish.",
            "answers": [
                "Declarative",
                "Interrogative",
                "Imperative",
                "Exclamatory"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "561f98b0f0974ced86d0f23d1a6ad9ee"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mount Everest is ……………………. peak in the world.",
            "description": "The superlative is used with the.",
            "answers": [
                "highest",
                "the highest",
                "the higher",
                "the high"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "80d4853411fc416280d537ddcd3606f5"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had a car, I ……………………. you a lift.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "can give",
                "could give",
                "could have given"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5eeae6008677433683ec59181fc16b8b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Please write ……………………",
            "description": "Legible is an adjective legibly is the adverb.",
            "answers": [
                "legible",
                "legibly",
                "legibily"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c40d22abb66c4619ac859c65bf3160b2"
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me why …………………….. crying.",
            "description": "The subject goes before the auxiliary verb in reported questions. ",
            "answers": [
                "was I",
                "am I",
                "I was",
                "I am"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "177c69f6af89447ab03d5bc69e511daf"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………… their best efforts, they could not save him.",
            "description": "Despite or in spite of is correct here.",
            "answers": [
                "Inspite of",
                "Despite",
                "Despite of"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1bd08f7c549244dfb195f141c587454b"
        },
        {
            "question": "They failed to properly ………………….. her illness.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "discover",
                "invent",
                "identify",
                "diagnose"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "1dd7968f4832460c81a36cb06a082bf5"
        },
        {
            "question": "He rarely visits you, ……………………?",
            "description": "Non-negative tags are used after negative expressions like rarely or hardly.",
            "answers": [
                "does he",
                "doesn't he",
                "did he"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "effda4c71f7d431fa8bc73d25d8dc15b"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the expression ‘devil’s advocate’ mean?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "support the rich",
                "support the poor",
                "support the counter argument"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0df2e585b81f4315830cdc2f2b83294c"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is high time you ……………………. up smoking.",
            "description": "We use a past tense after it is time with a present meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "gave",
                "give",
                "have given"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c126c26519cc449fb7f65807aa1e0a4b"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the expression ‘mano a mano’ mean?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to avoid a confrontation",
                "to get into a fight",
                "to confront each other directly"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "edce4643f7ab4f318494da04a0480a19"
        }
    ]
}